[handbrake releasing]
[car starting]
[engine revving]
[Jerry] This is a 1959
Fiat Jolly in coral orange.
It has a two-cylinder,
22-horsepower engine
that can reach a speed of up to
65 miles per hour with no doors.
It does have a rear body panel
in the event of an accident
to hold your kids inside
for an extra second
before they are also hurled into oblivion.
Only 100 to 200 Fiat Jollys were built,
and believe it or not,
they are quite sought after these days.
The word "jolly" means "joker" in Italian.
It also means something light, fun, funny
and pretty in several other languages.
"Insane" might have been a better name.
Even Italians have
varied opinions about it.
[in Italian]
What kind of car is this? It's so small!
But look how nice this is.
Do you see what the seats are like?
It's not supposed to be a Cadillac!
In my opinion, this isn't a real car.
So what are you talking about?
[in English] Where you want to go,
the Alps with this car?
[in Italian] It's for the beach!
If you like it, that's okay,
but I don't like it at all.
Fine, then. Go take a walk.
[Jerry] This car's like a puppy
that sticks its nose under your hand
because it wants to be petted.
Hitler would love this car.
[phone ringing]
-[Louis] Hello?
-Louis? It's Jerry.
[Louis] Jerry, what's going on?
[Jerry] Remember we talked about
going out on your boat?
[Louis] Yeah.
[Jerry] Do you have a coffee machine
on your boat?
[Louis] I do. I can make you coffee
on the boat, sure.
[Jerry] Great. On my way.
[Jerry] Hi, I'm Jerry Seinfeld
and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Today my guest is Louis C.K.
Louis is a fantastic stand-up comedian,
who also has his own show
that he writes, stars and directs,
which is also called Louie.
On today's show,
you're gonna see Louis do something
I'm sure you had no idea he could do.
[handbrake pulled]
[door opens]
We all set?
You wouldn't be here
if you weren't all set.
-[Jerry] So I got a car.
-[Louis] Oh, my God.
-[Louis] What kind of engine is in there?
-It's a two-cylinder.
It's a two-cylinder?
-Like an old motorcycle.
-Yeah.
One for me, one for you.
[laughing]
[Jerry] Can you imagine walking into
a car dealership and going,
-"Yeah, I'll take that."
-[Louis laughing]
How's it in the snow? How's the wicker?
-"How's the wicker in the snow?"
-In the snow?
[car starting]
-That's how you start it?
-Yeah.
Wow.
Okay, you're not gonna believe this,
but we're moving.
That's amazing.
[Louis] The guy on the bicycle
almost took you out.
[honking]
[honking back]
What a horn.
[tires screeching]
Now I feel like I'm in Italy.
[Jerry] This must be pretty funny looking.
[Louis] From outside? Yeah.
This is ridiculous.
It might be the worst car ever
to be driven in Manhattan.
I'd be hard-pressed to think
of something less appropriate.
[Louis] I like that I could actually
drag my knuckles on the street.
-[Jerry] You could touch the street.
-You could play polo.
[honking]
-Really?
-[honking]
How can you get mad at this car?
It's funny, people are right there.
There's a bicyclist.
My face is at his ass level.
-Go ahead, give it a little squeeze.
-No, I'm afraid.
[both laughing]
-[Louis] We've known each other for...
-[Jerry] Twenty years?
[Louis] More than that. Because I opened
for you at Stitches in Boston.
And I was, like, 19 years old.
-Do you consider yourself a New Yorker?
-New York is my home for sure.
Boston is distant from me.
And also I came to Boston from Mexico
when I was a kid.
And what is it
you would like to know about me?
[laughing]
[Jerry] I don't know why people
always assume the guest
is more interesting than the host.
I desperately wanted to go
to New York University Film School...
-Really?
-and be a filmmaker.
I wanted that desperately.
But I couldn't fill out...
the form at my high school.
And I would get, like,
some food on it or something.
And then I just would never do it.
[Jerry] How many years you think
you'll do your show?
I'd say seven or eight, tops.
Why? Why would you ever stop?
You stopped after nine years.
Yeah, but your show's different.
Your show can grow with you.
My show was about four single people...
-Yeah. Right.
-...living this certain type of lifestyle.
We didn't wanna do
Kramer's 50th birthday party.
[laughing]
Do you think you'll
ever shave this thing off?
I tried once. I did it for a movie.
My chin just goes from here to my neck.
Looks like a fine chin to me.
Well, thank you.
Most comedians do not have facial hair.
-How do you-- What are you basing that on?
-It's very unusual.
Have you thought that before you just
said it? Or did you just...
I like the story
of Chris Rock going on SNL.
Him telling Lorne,
"I wanna keep my mustache and goatee."
And Lorne said to him,
"In comedy, we put on beards."
[both laughing]
If we got hit by an SUV,
we would just be smears.
-Yeah.
-We would just be
pink and red smears
with teeth stuck in it.
And a Nike logo.
Would anybody do
a roadside memorial for us?
I don't think anybody would.
[Jerry] Have you noticed the white painted
bicycles? That's what those are.
That's a person that died on a bike?
-Oh, jeez.
-I know, it's like, "Come on.
Must we all get bummed
every day back and forth to work?"
It sometimes doesn't work out.
[laughing]
Sometimes, it doesn't work out.
Is this your boat?
-[bleep] No.
-[Jerry] That's the Utopia 3.
-[Louis] Utopia 3.
-[Jerry] That the worst sign
-you've seen on the side of a boat?
-[Louis] The ugliest...
-That's like a disco in Germany.
-Yeah. [laughing]
People with boats
usually have very bad taste.
-My ass hurts a lot.
-From the wicker?
I hope so.
[Louis laughing]
How would your life be different
if you had a 100 times the amount
of money that you have?
I'd probably use it to make stuff.
I'd probably have...
You know, I'd make movies
with my own money probably.
Max Bialystock said,
"Never put your money in the show."
Yeah, well, he's not a great role model.
[Louis] I'm amazed
at this massive structure.
It's the most prominent structure
on the river of Manhattan.
And it catches one golf ball like this.
That's all it does.
[Jerry] We're not gonna
fill up the river with balls.
[Louis] No.
Wouldn't that be funny if it topped out,
filled with golf balls?
-The whole river.
-Yeah.
We could just walk to New Jersey
on golf balls.
Or you put them over in Jersey,
and hit them back.
[Louis laughing]
-Larry played golf with the president.
-He did.
Here's how my relationship works
with Larry David.
We were on the phone for a half hour,
two days ago,
and it didn't come up.
[laughing]
Where we going? We went the wrong way?
No, I just think you would look great
in that shirt.
-The colors, with your hair.
-I don't look good in orange.
Really? You are orange.
I know, that's why. It's too much.
Too much of a good thing.
[Louis] This guy Alex,
he lives on his boat.
He helps me with my boat and stuff.
He's like my boat guy.
[Jerry] Wow! That is handsome.
You know what it looks like?
-It looks like the orca from Jaws.
-[Louis] I always wanted the orca.
Do you ever lean over the side and go,
"That's a 20-footer."
And you go, "Twenty-five."
"Twenty-five."
I don't think suede is the right fabric
for boating.
No, it really isn't.
[Louis] See these things?
These are fenders.
Once we're past the Queen Mary thing here,
you gotta pull all the fenders up
and just lay them.
That's all you gotta do.
Aye, me hearties.
Okay, here go the engines.
[engine starts]
[engine revving]
Comedy eyeball, don't forget that.
You need that?
-No, that stays in here.
-Okay.
Yeah, that's how I can see
what's going on down here.
Wow.
-This is the flybridge.
-This does not look easy.
Whenever I'm with my kids
and I do this part of coming out of here,
-I'm always yelling at them to shut up.
-Right.
'Cause if they start chatting, I'm like,
"Shut up. You're really making this hard!
-I love you. Stop it."
-[Jerry laughs]
[Jerry] I think you like boats
because you look good on a boat.
-Look at you, you're Quint.
-[Louis] I am Quint.
[Jerry laughs]
[engine revving]
Backing up.
[Jerry] Your eyes are darting around
like you're a fugitive.
A lot of it is breathing.
[exhales and laughs]
[Louis] This is a mother [bleep] today.
Pulling me right towards
all that rotting wood.
-Why don't they get rid of that?
-It would be really hard.
Like pulling teeth out of a serpent's head
or something. I don't know.
[Jerry] Is there gambling on that boat?
[Louis] I think you're gambling
every time you go out on it.
[Jerry] Wow. I can't believe
how well you did that.
-[Louis] Thank you.
-That was masterful.
All right, so now you need to go
get the fenders up.
Okay. Now I'm Richard Dreyfuss.
[Louis] "It proves that a college boy
don't know when to admit when he's wrong."
-I lost the fenders.
-You lost them?
I was playing with the comedy eyeball.
[chuckling]
-They're gone? It's all right.
-They're gone.
Now we're doing 16 knots,
which is great on the river.
-[Jerry] You're having a blast now?
-[Louis] Very happy.
[Jerry] Why?
[Louis]
I didn't used to be able to do this.
But it's amazing to me
that you can just take a boat...
And over time,
figure out all this [bleep] .
And the more things you can do,
you can go anywhere.
I love that, and I love
coming out on the river.
I'm the only person out here.
[jazz music playing]
-You wanna do all of them?
-No, just do the sides.
Like your kid's jacket in the winter.
Yeah, upside down at 20 knots.
[laughing] Upside down.
[Jerry] How many shows have you got
figured out so far?
Ten of them, I've finished writing.
And I took on a couple
of new people to try.
They sit on my couch while I write,
and it's somebody to talk to.
And this time I used Steven Wright.
Oh, yeah?
When I grew up in Boston,
when I started doing stand-up,
-he was everybody's hero.
-Sure.
So you wanted to humiliate him
by having him work for you now,
on a couch.
[Jerry] Steven and I did a gig in the '80s
at a college football stadium,
called Gator Growl, 80,000 people.
George Burns had done it the year before.
-What did George Burns do at Gator Growl?
-Twenty minutes.
But Steven had a great line.
They were asking us,
"What's it like as a comedian
in front of 80,000 people?"
-Right.
-And Steven said,
"If you're swimming in the ocean,
it doesn't matter how deep the water is.
All you can do is swim."
[laughs]
I get really weirded out
going under big bridges.
They have this commercial now
for this drug called Chantix.
And they list all the side effects,
which is the worst comedy premise,
of course.
-Yeah, of course.
-But I've never heard another one
where they say,
"You may experience weird dreams."
-"Weird dreams."
-Weird dreams.
-What dreams aren't weird?
So I kind of imagine they have like,
a little phone bank set up at Chantix
-with people calling in with their dreams.
-Right.
"Bob, you think that one's weird?
I got a guy here with orangutan feet."
"No, I've had that one."
[laughing]
"It's not weird."
[Louis] I think we should
maybe anchor over here.
[Jerry] That sounds good.
-I can't afford this boat.
-No?
-I shouldn't have gotten it.
-Come on!
Well, you shouldn't buy a yacht
unless you can afford ten yachts.
-There's some kind of formula like that.
-That's stupid.
-Is it? All right, good.
-Yes.
-When I hit the water, just go like this.
-Okay.
If the chain starts going off to the side,
just go like this or like this.
[anchor chain rattling]
[anchor drop]
[Louis] I lost an anchor under here once.
Maybe James Cameron will find it.
-You want a coffee?
-Yeah.
-[Louis] Cappuccino or espresso?
-Cappuccino.
-You really like things, don't you?
-Yeah, I like machines.
-Yeah.
-I like the things that make stuff happen.
[Louis] I was with my kids
waiting for a school bus
and this dog walked by
with his owner, on the leash.
The owner walked by
with his dog on a leash.
"The dog walked by
with an owner on the leash"?
I said it backwards
and then tried to fix it.
[Jerry] My favorite dog thing is when
your dog is walking through the room,
and you stop him,
he doesn't then continue on his way.
-Whatever you interrupted is gone.
-It's gone.
[Louis] I go to the 3D IMAX movies stoned.
-[Jerry] Stoned or you get a scone?
-[giggling]
Yes, I get a scone to see a 3D IMAX movie.
-You're so elegant.
-Yeah.
If my kids have been with me for a stretch
and then they go with their mom
and I have a day between them
and some work to do or something,
I smoke some pot and see a 3D IMAX movie.
Bring your own snacks
or do you get movie crap?
I don't get the movie crap
because I don't want to buy it stoned.
To me, talking to a stranger
when I'm stoned is like a nightmare.
Why, because you can't read the signals?
Yeah, I just can't, it's all wrong,
and they're looking at me
like I'm crazy, I think.
And what's worse is if people recognize me
for being a known person
and they come over, "Oh, my God!"
And I'm really stoned.
So why do you go
to a crowded movie theater?
[laughs] I have it down to a science.
First, I buy the tickets online.
I print it out, and I put it
in the same pocket every time,
so I'm not doing this
"Stoned guy can't find his thing."
This pocket has no other function.
-It's got that ticket in it.
-One ticket for one guy.
One ticket for one guy.
I get some candy bars and treats.
Like, an ice cream bar is good.
You put that in one pocket,
maybe a Mounds bar or Snickers.
You have to wear a jacket
to do this right.
-It's like a suicide bomber.
-[chuckles] Yes.
-The detonator's in here.
-It's the same preparation.
I just get Uber,
the car service, to get me.
I like to lower the window about halfway
and just look at people
on the streets of Manhattan.
When you're stoned,
that's an amazing thing to look at.
People carrying their bags of stuff,
and just seeing them and going,
"We're just worms,
and we're just carrying our worm meal."
And I go in and give
the lady my paper ticket.
And I put on the crazy glasses,
and I sit here.
And then the great thing,
this is all I'm at it for.
They show trailers regular size,
and you get lost in that.
And then when it's time for the movie,
that screen grows...
-Yeah.
-...and they have this 3D IMAX countdown.
Where the numbers come at you
and envelop you.
And it's all blue and crystal,
and it drives me crazy.
It's my favorite thing in life.
It's like sex, comedy when it's good...
-Sex.
-Yeah.
-Comedy.
The blue numbers.
-Yeah, sex is starting to go a bit down.
-And sex is dropping.
[giggling]
-Yes.
-That's a shame.
-When sex gets below the blue numbers...
-Yeah.
-I have, you know...
-Pull the ripcord.
[Jerry] Know what the first thing
I said as a child,
before I said, "Mama" or "Dada"?
"Go [bleep] yourself."
I said, "Leave me alone."
[giggling]
That's amazing. My God.
But is that not the mantra
of stand-up comedy?
Leave me alone,
okay?
You know, people talk about kids today.
How they grow up too fast.
I feel like I can only take a year
of each year. It can't...
[chuckling]
"No more of you as a 9-year-old.
I've had it. Get me a 10-year-old."
I don't know,
I sometimes miss the older versions...
-Sure, yeah.
-I look back.
You can miss anything in life, Louis.
Yeah, you can, even if it's bad.
I had that thought this morning 'cause
my oldest is going to middle school.
It's a real schlep now, the morning,
and I thought,
"This is gonna be a tough winter."
Then my second thought was,
"I'm gonna miss this.
There's gonna be a day
where I'm not gonna do this again."
That's very rich, Louis.
-That's good stuff, right?
-That's good stuff, man.
There's the George Washington Bridge
shadow over us.
[Jerry] Scary bridge moment.
Look how beautiful
Riverside Drive is up here.
-I love those buildings.
-Yeah.
New York makes me crazy.
-I love New York City.
-Yeah.
I love the different brick colors
and the water towers.
Yeah.
And then the trees
and then rocks right before the river.
I know.
[Louis] I ran this boat aground
in Harlem once, in the mud.
It was the first time
my kids were on my boat.
And I see this little cove, and I say,
"Let's go in the cove,
and I'll make some macaroni and cheese."
-I'm so happy to show my kids the boat.
-[Jerry] Right.
[Louis] I'm also nervous
they're not gonna like it.
We run right into a [bleep] mud...
We just go right in the mud.
It was low tide,
I didn't read the chart correctly.
I'm in mud.
There's a park 30 feet away,
people barbecuing.
And there's a park ranger
and he yells out,
"You're stuck there. It's low tide.
You're stuck till, like, midnight."
My kids are really crying now.
I'm like, "Shut up," to the guy.
And I get on the radio and I go,
"Coast guard."
I thought the coast guard would come
dig me out.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
-But they didn't even answer.
[Louis] Now the water's receded so much
that there's mud all around me.
The police boat is in the water
and the guy yells across,
"Are your kids okay?"
And I go, "They're all right."
He asks if I could get out
and walk on the mud.
I took a pole and I feel,
it's like quicksand.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
-[Louis] Would've died in the mud.
People are starting to form at the park,
starting to figure out who I am.
[Jerry laughing]
And the cops say, "Are your kids hungry?"
I go, "Yeah, we don't have a lot of--"
We can't run the generator,
so we can't cook the macaroni and cheese.
So they've got hard macaroni and water,
that's all we have.
So the cops left and went to Whole Foods,
and they got us a chicken
and all kinds of food.
But now there was a big expanse of mud
between me and them.
I needed to throw them a line.
I throw them the line
and it's not getting there.
I pull it back and now I'm covered in mud.
I put a pot on the line, and I'm
swinging it and trying to throw it.
And people on the shore are going,
"You can do it, Louis."
All these Hispanic people from Harlem.
And then it would go in the mud
and they'd go, "You suck, man."
They're all, "Boo!"
And finally the cops see a fisherman
in a fishing boat.
They turn on their lights, they pull him
over, and they get him on their boat,
and he casts me a line
with a weight on it.
And I tied my rope to his line,
and he pulled my line in.
And then they tied a big garbage bag,
with food in it, to the line,
and I stood on the back of the boat.
And it was the hardest thing I ever did,
physically, in my life.
But I wanted to feed my kids.
I was so desperate to feed my kids.
And I pull this and people are cheering.
It was insane.
My oldest daughter was like,
"Daddy, take all your clothes off
in the shower of the boat."
She gave me water bottles
and I cleaned off.
Then we ate,
and we were there till midnight.
This started at one o'clock.
We were there for almost 12 hours.
At one point it started raining,
while I was just sitting, waiting.
It's dead quiet now,
and I hear, in the park, some kid go,
"Louis C.K., it's raining now!"
And then this guy
who lives on his boat, he came...
-That's how I met him.
-[Jerry] You called?
[Louis] I called, said, "Do you have
anybody that can help me?"
He was dropped in the water
by a motorboat. He's a river fish.
So he just jumped in the river
and swam to me,
crawled on the mud, stood on my swim deck,
and took off his dirty clothes, got into
some clean clothes he had in a bag.
-And he helped me get out of there.
-How did he do it?
[Louis] He knows everything.
He had a sense when the boat
was starting to get some movement.
So we used the bow thrusters
to pull it around.
And then when we got loose,
we just gunned it out of there.
The next day,
our picture was in the paper.
Daily News, a picture of me and my kids
on the boat, stuck in the mud.
And I say to my oldest,
"We have to come out
on the boat again soon,
-so you can have a good experience."
-[Jerry] Right.
[Louis] She said,
"We had a good experience."
[Jerry laughing]
She was so happy.
That is one of the great stories.
-Boy. That'll make a man out of you.
-Yeah.
[Louis] Well, out of my daughters, anyway.
[Jerry chuckling]
You know, we both did that big fancy
Robin Hood benefit at the Javits Center.
Yeah, I got mad at them.
-Elton John opened the show.
-Right.
-And he played "Tiny Dancer."
-Yeah.
And "Bennie and the Jets."
And they were talking at their tables.
Nobody was even looking at him.
And so, when I went on I said,
"Well, I'm very excited to perform for you
after you talked through Elton John
like he was a piano player
in the Hilton lounge."
With all due respect to Elton John,
-why don't you tell us who Bennie is?
-Right.
You know, is this a drug story,
-what is it?
-Is it actual jets?
-Is it a gay story?
-Right.
Is that a gay bar?
Are those all penises?
-I'm just saying...
-But penises don't have wings.
[giggling]
-They will, if it gets any worse.
-[laughing] "They will."
[laughing]
[Louis] You just see.
[both laughing]
-Here, do me a favor, will you?
-Sure.
[giggles] Open my door for me.
I don't want people
to know where I live.
-So just the top one.
-All right, Louis, I'll see you later.
Just the top lock at first.
It goes to the left, till it clicks.
There you go.
And then this one towards the knob.
[keys clicks]
-There you go.
-All right, see you.
-All right.
-You wanna come in?
-Can I use the bathroom? Yeah. Thank you.
-Yeah.
[Jerry] Hey, how do you know how
to do the locks to my house?